<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Teaching Resources on Static Web Publishing for Digital Scholarship</title><link>/teaching-resources/</link><description>Recent content in Teaching Resources on Static Web Publishing for Digital Scholarship</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/teaching-resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lesson Plan</title><link>/teaching-resources/lesson-plan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/teaching-resources/lesson-plan/</guid><description>This lesson plan provides an assortment of learning modules for teaching static web technologies for digital scholarship and scholarly communications librarianship. Each topic includes a learning objective and recommended readings, viewings, or tutorials for use in workshops or seminars.
Download PDF Download DOCX Topics:
Introduction Benefits for Digital Scholarship Challenges and Drawbacks Static vs Dynamic Websites Plain Text vs Rich Text Static Websites and Accessibility Static Websites in Context Popular Static Site Generators Recommendations for Math Open Infrastructure for Scholarly Communications Community Engagement Introduction Learning Objective: Participants will be able to recognize the strengths and limitations that static websites provide scholarly communications librarians.</description></item><item><title>Bibliography</title><link>/teaching-resources/bibliography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/teaching-resources/bibliography/</guid><description>This annotated bibliography provides an overview of how static websites can be used for scholarly purposes. It includes publications representing a variety of communities, including libraries, digital humanities, and open source software. The citations included in this bibliography &amp;ndash;with few exceptions&amp;ndash; focus on librarians and scholars who use static websites for their work.
Download PDF Download DOCX Articles Tutorials Podcasts Articles Becker, Devin, Evan Williamson, and Olivia Wikle.</description></item></channel></rss>